Shawn Rice

Portland, OR (503) 964-5695 shawnrice2332@gmail.com

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/shawn-r-systems-science/

Portfolio: https://lqq3.github.io/srPortfolio/ Github: https://github.com/IQQ3

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY:

Technical Project Manager with over 20 years of experience working in various capacities for both large corporations and small-midsize organizations. My career history has been primarily in Networking, Security, and Infrastructure, but my recent career is centered around Data. I enjoy a challenge which requires multi-field expertise. Open to FTE or Contract opportunities.

EDUCATION AND CERTIFICATIONS:

Portland State University - 2019
Bachelor's degree, Systems Science

Sophos Certified Engineer - 2020 Sophos Cybersecurity

Cisco Certified Network Associate / Professional (CCNA/CCNP) - 2001 Cisco Networking Academy

Lane Community College - 1996

Associate's Degree, Electronics Engineering Technician

Duke University, Psychology Dept. & Applied Behavior Analysis Intl. - Feb 2022 Guest Panelist, Subject Matter Expert & DEI Advocate - ABA & Neurodivergence Conference

Duke University, Psychology Dept. & Applied Behavior Analysis Intl. - May 2022

Guest Panelist, Subject Matter Expert & DEI Advocate - "Neurodivergence in the Workplace"

Summit

TECHNICAL SKILLS:

Microsoft Suite (Development) Microsoft Azure / SharePoint / DevOps

Cloud Architecture Network Architecture & Routing

Virtualization & Containerization DevSecOps

SQL, Python, R, Javascript, jQuery MS365, AWS, GCP

Web API HTML, XML, YAML, CSS, PHP

Information Security Database Engineering & Troubleshooting

Data Science Project Management

Technical Writing Systems Analysis

Power BI & Tableau Agile

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:

Business Systems Analyst II / Software Quality Analyst

City of Portland, Revenue Division

Dec 2021 - May 2022

- I was contracted as a team-of-one to analyze and resolve tenacious and elusive data problems within their databases. These were all ongoing problems, mostly with stored procedures experienced by Portland's Mayoral and City Leadership teams.
- I interviewed all stakeholders, performed various Analysis methods, located all problems and delivered solutions to 100% of them in 50% of the projected time.

Technologies & Skills

Business Systems Analysis, CI/CD, Agile & Scrum; MSSQL, SSMS, SSAS, SSRS; MS Power & DevOps stacks; XML; Java, JavaScript, jQuery and both REST and SOAP APIs using Postman and CLI

Principle DevSecOps & Project Manager Computers Made Easy Managed IT Services

Dec 2019 - Jun 2021

- I graduated from PSU into the COVID-pandemic, and quickly started work for Computers Made Easy. It
 became my solo task to estimate risks & costs for, create bids, design and execute plans to move our 200+
 customer-companies to an "online" paradigm. I performed Gap, State, Cost/Risk/Benefit, SWOT and other
 analysis for companies to use for decisions about their best strategy for large infrastructure investment
 during the "Pandemic Business Model changes".
- In the end, I successfully migrated all 200+ companies within 1 year using Systems Science and Data Analysis methods gained at Portland State University.

Technologies & Skills

Business & Business Systems Analysis, MS DevOps & Sysinternals, MS 365, Azure, SharePoint, MS Office Suite (Development in all apps), AWS, GCP, PowerBI, Tableau, Web API, ETL & Data Migration, Cloud Architecture, Security & Networking Tools, Virtualization, Containerization, PCI-DSS & HIPPA Compliance, Cisco Routers, Firewalls, NextGen Security, Windows AD & Group Policy, Linux

Systems Science Student

Portland State University

Aug 2014 - Jun 2019

• I returned to college to get a degree in Systems Science (the science of analyzing complexity within combinatorial and dynamic systems; Data Science is a subsection of Systems Science and a primary tool), where I used Python, R, and MATLAB to study Machine Learning & AI for advanced empirical analysis, predictive modeling, systems mapping, and data visualization.

Technologies & Skills

Empirical, Statistical, Quantitative/Qualitative & Process Analysis, Data Science & Analysis, Python, R, MATLAB, SQL, ETL, Data Warehousing Concepts & Practices, GitHub, Document Design, AI & Machine Learning

Support Technician

Support.com

Feb 2010 - Jan 2014

I remotely resolved SMB and Consumer problems including hardware diagnosis, security, networking
and database software administration and repair. Technical versatility, fast-but-accurate diagnosis,
thorough note-taking and project-planning were all expected and metered. Tasks involved Networking
Solutions, Virus Removal, acting on Security Threats, Server/Workstation Repair, User Training, and
more.

Technologies & Skills

Business Systems Analysis, End-point Protection, IDS/IPS, Firewalls, Security Information and Event Management (SIEM), Vulnerability Management Tools, Registry Diving, ETL & Data Migration, Manual Virus Removal, Windows AD & Group Policy, Linux

Sr. Software Engineer

JSH. Inc., LLC.

Nov 2008 - Jan 2010

It was my responsibility to create a more user-friendly "Persistent LiveUSB" allowing a wider target-user
base including novices. I was to invent and implement driver-level changes and routines, and privacy
protocols for our product creating an easy to access and reliably secured environment for our users.
Ultimately I flew to Dallas, Tx and presented the product to the Chief Architect of Factory Systems at AMD /
Global Foundries.

Technologies & Skills

C++; Python; Javascript; HTML; XML; JSON; Bash CLI; Linux; GitHub; Documentation & Knowledge-base Curation; User Instructions for all facets of the project; Drafting and reviewing technical, policy, procedures, standards, and audit documentation; End-point Protection; Firewalls, IDS/IPS, Security Information and Event Management

Network Analyst *Kaiser Permanente*

Mar 2008 - Oct 2008

It was my responsibility to locate, replicate and distribute over 7,000 computers in the Pacific Northwest. The
functions ranged from "desktop database access" to highly-specialized medical equipment, such as MRI
interfaces and others. I was also to generate a granular daily time-line detailing the execution of, and
reporting of the Computer Asset Refresh Team. It was also my duty to curate the knowledge-base. Knowing
and following HIPAA guidelines was necessary.

Technologies & Skills

Epic Medical Recording, PXE Servers, Javascript, SQL, ETL and Data Migration, HIPPA Compliance, Systems Analysis, Active Domain, Windows Groups & Policies, IDS/IPS, SEIM, Technical Writing & Documentation, Leadership

MIS Manager & Business Systems Analyst

Carson Oil Co.

Mar 2005 - Nov 2006

At Carson Oil, I was the Project Manager for all new projects as well as their Systems Analyst, Security,
Disaster Response and Network Infrastructure Architect. I was additionally responsible for the ETL of all new
databases upon the purchase of a company; and for the upkeep of several full-stack programs for both
internal and customer access of our billing and records.

Technologies & Skills

C++, SQL, ETL, PCI-DSS, IDS / IPS, Web API, PCL & SCADA Controllers, Monitoring & Dashboards, Telemetry, Business Systems Analysis, Petrochemical Analysis, Adv. Networking Concepts & Security, Pentesting, Windows AD & Group Policy, Linux, Technical Writing, Leadership.

Business Systems Analyst & Systems Architect

Pacific Solutions

Feb 2004 - Mar 2005

 At Pacific Solutions, I was the entirety of the Business Systems department. I was the Project Manager for all new undertakings, went onsite to perform an assessment of the business needs, planned, implemented, deployed and trained users for all business systems. This included servers, databases, networking, security, custom applications, as well as business routines and operations.

Technologies & Skills

PCI-DSS, Access Control, Windows Active Directory & Group Policy, Linux, Security & Networking, Pentesting, Business Systems Analysis, Documentation, ETL & Data Migration

Business Systems Analyst & Systems Architect

Metropolitan Communications

Jan 2002 - May 2003

 At Metropolitan Communications, I was the Project Manager and Business Systems Analyst. I interviewed stakeholders to discover business needs and used the information to plan and implement full topologies including networking, servers, PBX Phone Systems, security both logical and physical, full-stack programing (often a SQL database and an HTML/ Javascript/JQuery/PHP front-end), and business policies and procedures. I was often hired to train customer-companies' managers and owners in Project and/or Data Management skills and Data Visualization.

Technologies & Skills

PCI-DSS, Access Control, Windows Active Directory & Group Policy, Linux, Security & Networking, Pentesting, Business Systems Analysis, Documentation, ETL & Data Migration

Business Systems Analyst & Systems Architect

Crossroads Espresso

Jan 2000 - Aug 2001

- At Crossroads Espresso, I was engaged to replace and update their entire network including hardware, network and software. I created an interactive knowledge-base which led to a shopping cart. This was a manual task of creation for both the site and the shopping cart at this point in time. While doing so, it was incumbent on me to learn the art of Commercial Espresso Machine repair, making me one of the first 10 in America.
- I created a phone support line and website for plumbers and electricians who were asked to repair the newto-America machines. We serviced and supplied parts for all brands but specialized in La Pavoni. I set up the Service Center for Crossroads and trained the technicians as well.

Technologies & Skills

PCI-DSS, Access Control, Windows Active Directory & Group Policy, Linux, Security & Networking, Pentesting, Business Systems Analysis, Documentation, ETL & Data Migration, Webpage and Shopping Cart design, troubleshooting, leadership

Technical Support Representative

Symantec

Jun 1998 - Dec. 1999

While at Symantec, I acted as technical support for all products, and manually removed pernicious viruses.

Technologies & Skills

Troubleshooting, Customer Service, Networking, Windows & Mac software repair, RDP, VOIP (H.323), Networking Protocols

Systems Analyst & Electronics Engineer

Broadcast Software Intl.

Apr 1997 - May 1998

At Broadcast Software Inc, we automated full Radio Stations using custom hardware and software. My task
was to survey the site, and return with a plan for implementation. I assisted with the software side, but
primarily designed and created custom rack-mounted circuit-boards for integration, playback and automation
tasks. I would then retrofit the software to match the needs of the individual business, and deploy it all. I was
also responsible for customer training.

Technologies & Skills

Electronics Engineering, Javascript, Business Systems Analysis, Systems Engineering

Computer Technician

Castle Computers

Apr 1995 - Jun 1997

At Castle Computers, I was a Computer Technician and Salesperson. As a customer-facing representative, I would facilitate intake, sales and outgoing computers, upkeep the storefront, make sales & repair recommendations and to repair computers. I was also trained to do the inventory ordering and management.

Technologies & Skills

Windows and Windows Networking, Customer Support, Sales, Vendor Relations and Stock Management